Afton N. Burton

Phone: 714-306-4399 Email: afton.burton5@gmail.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE

As a Payer Specialist with over 5 years of experience working with insurance companies regarding patient claims and a Bachelor's Degree in Business, I have had success driving revenue through strategic team work and analyzing payer behaviors. I am seeking to utilize my analytical expertise and leadership experience as an Analyst, Strategic Development for Taco Bell.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DaVita, Inc. Payer Specialist

February 2016 - present

- Analyze Medicare Advantage claims behavior to identify revenue cycle discrepancies and obtain more accurate reimbursement
- Partner with Payer Contracting to identify payer contract opportunities and establish payment rates bringing in over \$1M in unexpected AR
- Effectively navigate the US Department of Veteran's Affairs system, leading to quicker payment turnaround time
- Coordinate and organize meetings across teams and keep minutes for meetings to ensure timely follow-up to actions
- Assisted with onboarding of new teammates and performed behavior based interviews

DaVita, Inc.

Patient Accounts Specialist

April 2015 - February 2016

- Managed billing and collections for multiple DaVita clinics, working closely with various insurance payers
- Built relationships within the internal core team and partnered with associates in order to effectively process an average of 650 claims per month with over 20% of claims being resolved
- Negotiated claims with insurance companies resulting in deep knowledge of multiple insurance products

Roy D. Nini, MD

Executive Assistant

July 2012 - April 2015

- Managed patient appointment times across five office locations
- Processed billing for more than 500 patients and ensured payments were handled in a timely manner
- Created and maintained new system for accessing patient charts online, well ahead of schedule as dictated by the HITECH act allowing MD to receive cash incentives
- Worked closely with various attorneys, physical therapists, and Worker's Compensation adjusters resulting in numerous
 referred patients to the practice and long-term relationships

Wells Fargo Bank

Business Specialist

March 2006 - April 2012

- Built and maintained long-term relationships with existing customers, resulting in higher than average client retention for the branch and numerous referrals received by those customers
- Worked with management on large projects training employees how to improve customer retention and how to deep dive into
 customer account in order to increase revenue for the branch by offering products that fit the client's needs
- Knowledgeable in over 50 personal and business banking products offered by Wells Fargo

SKILLS/COMMITTEES

- Proficient in Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access, Outlook
- Lead on Payer
 Contracting Team
- Lead on Duals
 Team
- Logistics Lead on Innovation Committee
- Green Team Captain
- Lead on VA Team

EDUCATION

CALIFORNIA STATE UNIVERSITY, FULLERTON - BS in Business Finance Degree

FULLERTON COLLEGE - Associates Degree